<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>…delirium Mk. III</title>
    <description>The mental wanderings continue.
</description>
    <link>http://razorclown.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://razorclown.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 14:12:57 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 14:12:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Over &quot;Getting Over&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The name of the game in professional wrestling is “getting over” with the crowd. Up until that point, you do whatever it takes to get them to love you (if you’re a good guy) or hate you (if you’re a heel).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re “over,” it’s different. You’ve shown the crowd what to expect from you, and they’re on board. They’re in. They’re with you, whether they’re cheering or booing. You can have an off night or be in a bad storyline and they won’t just abandon you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t feel like I’m over with anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with friends that I’ve known for years, I have this anxiety over how I will perform. As far as my heart is concerned, I’m always one dumb comment away from rejection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my dating years, this outlook did me no good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, once I found my wife — wife-to-be at the time — I noticed something different: I wasn’t nervous around her. I wasn’t desperate to find out if she were the woman I had been searching for. I allowed myself to be myself in a way I never had, and now, here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After nearly seven years of marriage, I’m more insecure now than I was then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, she knows me. She knows everything about me. And she’s done a lot of life with me. That is, I’ve put her through a lot. That leaves me expecting that, at any moment, I’ll deposit the last straw on the camel’s back, and she’ll be done with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I treat myself like the crowds on TV treat John Cena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Cena has been the top guy at WWE for ten years for a reason. He is consistently cited as being the hardest working person on the roster. He consistently has good matches when it counts. He uses his talent to benefit others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, whenever he makes his entrance, the crowd is immediately split. You can literally hear it. The chants begin, interlocking like some inevitable drumbeat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s go, Cena!” / “Cena sucks!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s go, Cena!” / “Cena sucks!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because people are tired of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s been on top, and heavily featured, for ten years. It’s not that he’s bad. It’s that people have watched him for long enough that they have plenty to nitpick. Deal with the same thing for long enough, and the things that used to be cute are now deathly annoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s me with myself. I’m tired of my own crap. And it kills me when I see other people have the same thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what’s the answer? Obviously, my value is centered in the wrong place. I know this. It’s one of many things I believe, but fight to feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://razorclown.github.io/2016/03/07/getting-over.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://razorclown.github.io/2016/03/07/getting-over.html</guid>
        
        <category>mental health</category>
        
        <category>wrestling</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kingdom Dance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I watch the Kingdom Dance scene from &lt;em&gt;Tangled&lt;/em&gt;, I find myself near tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a fun movie. It’s full of humor and drama, and it has its fair share of sappy, heartstring-tugging moments. But for some reason, the Kingdom Dance is the one that gets me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tangled&lt;/em&gt; is Disney/Pixar’s take on the Rapunzel story. In this version, Rapunzel’s mother, the queen, becomes ill during her pregnancy, and the king saves her with a magic flower with healing powers. A wicked old woman, however, had been using the flower to keep her unnaturally young, so she kidnaps the young princess when she discovers that the flower’s healing powers have manifested in the child’s hair. Thus, Rapunzel is locked in a hidden tower, away from her royal family and her kingdom, and her hair — which loses its power when cut — grows long, as the story demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rapunzel is smart and charming, but utterly inexperienced in the ways of the world. She has been taught by Mother Gothel to be afraid of what goes on outside her life of seclusion, but her curiosity grows — especially around the floating lanterns that appear in the distance every year on her birthday (lit by the citizens of the kingdom in hopes that their princess will return). She finally leaves the tower in search of answers when a thief happens upon her and she enlists him as her guide to find the source of the lanterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their adventures, at last, lead them to the kingdom of her birth. At this point, Rapunzel has faced many of her long-established fears and overcome them: run-ins with ruffians and thugs, life-threatening peril, and — by far the most important and horrifying to her — standing up to her mother. She has shown herself to be what she has always been told she is not: capable of thriving in a tough world. And she’s beginning to embrace it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the part that moves me to tears. As Rapunzel’s roguish escort shows her around the city, she trails off behind a group of musicians wandering the street. By the time he looks up, the musicians have stopped wandering because Rapunzel is dancing in the town square. Moments later, she’s grabbing people one by one, tugging them in, and they join the dance. Moments after that, the entire town square is taken up by a massive folk dance and a throng of delighted onlookers. There is then a montage of Rapunzel and her guide: she takes in the city, shows her guide a stack of books by candlelight, and scrawls a giant, gorgeous chalk mural alongside the children. She is completely in her element, effortlessly confident, free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It slays me. But why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is some killer poetry going on in the narrative. The lost princess has followed the lights back to the kingdom, and she’s dancing with her subjects in the streets, but neither she nor they know it’s her. That’s pretty compelling in and of itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But maybe what gets me more than that is the change in Rapunzel. All her life, she has been taught to be afraid. But suddenly, she is home, and she is herself, perhaps for the first time. No fear. No pretense. Just pure, honest, innocent joy. And at the sight of it, everyone stops and stares, giving her the chance to pull others along with her joy until it spreads to all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if that’s a moment I desire for myself or what. My own life has been driven more by fear than joy. Maybe it’s just that I love to see that kind of beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m reminded of when I went to prom with a friend. Nothing remarkable in that — except that my friend had a condition that had damaged her hips. She walked with a severe limp. I figured there wouldn’t be much in the way of dancing. I wasn’t prepared. When she started to move, I stopped and stared. She was graceful. Confident. She owned it. It was one of the most beautiful things I have ever seen to this day. I’ll never forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe its the confidence that gets me. It takes something special to dance with joy and be unashamed, no matter what you look like when you’re doing it. I don’t have that. There’s a quote from &lt;em&gt;New Girl&lt;/em&gt; that sums me up perfectly: “If everyone goes to the ocean and runs into the water, I’m the guy on the beach watching the wallets.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of amazing things I would do if I weren’t so responsible. Like what? Quit my job and become a missionary in a comic book shop. Write a series of novels about a sword-wielding clown who fights necromancers. Learn to play heavy metal on a violin. Host a podcast with my gaming group about the triumphs and tragedies of roleplaying games. Blog about what it’s like to earnestly try to follow God when you think you’re a total waste of space and someone made a mistake by letting you become a pastor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever it is, Rapunzel speaks to me. That scene in &lt;em&gt;Tangled&lt;/em&gt; kills me. It stirs me. It makes something in me want to come out. To be free.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://razorclown.github.io/2015/11/12/kingdom-dance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://razorclown.github.io/2015/11/12/kingdom-dance.html</guid>
        
        <category>entertainment</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Indeterminate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I left the formal ministry just under a year ago, it was with an incredible sense of relief. Incredible not just because of its magnitude, but because of the hurricane of angst and doubt that led up to my decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t walking away from my faith. Not at all. The angst arose from the idea that leaving the pastoral position I was in would offend God and derail me from the plan He had for me. I was afraid that I would be failing my God, my family, my church, and myself. I was afraid that I would be ruining my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just under a year later, it hasn’t ruined my life. It hasn’t demolished my faith or my family. It has, however, exposed a whole lot of damage that I couldn’t see clearly while I was a pastor. Not that the position was the problem — it was my perspective on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pastoral career was marked by more fear and misery than joy. As afraid as I was to fail in leaving my position, I was constantly afraid of failing while I was in the position. Any criticism or correction confirmed my greatest fear, over and over: that I had become a spiritual leader not because of a divine calling, but because of a clerical error, a flaw in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was neck-deep in impostor syndrome, and it was draining the life out of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been living with unanswered doubts around my call to ministry ever since it began. When I initially interviewed with my local church board to be included in the ministerial preparation process, I was sure they would tell me to come back when I was more sure that God was directing me. When an experienced pastor told me that “you have to know that you know that you know” that you’re called to ministry, I froze inside. I never, at any point, had that level of confidence or clarity that God wanted me to become a minister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I constantly judged myself based on those questions. As I learned and tried my hand at ministry, every failure, every mistake convinced me that I wasn’t where I was so that I could become a productive, fruitful minister. After several years of being a pastor, and, in my eyes, dramatically underperforming, I had all but convinced myself that God has brought me to where I was so that I could serve as a negative example to the other ministerial students around me. I thought I was a living illustration of what not to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I literally thought that my purpose in ministry was to test the patience of the “real” ministers around me, the ones God had actually ordained to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, I never doubted that God had called me to the church and the situation where I became a pastor. I still don’t, though I think I may understand His call better in hindsight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of us were considering leaving our current church to go to this new church, possibly to take on leadership positions. We weren’t going to make the choice lightly. We had gone over to the church property to pray over it and listen for God’s direction. As I prayed, I asked God if I should make the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only a few moments in my life where I am fully confident that God spoke a particular phrase to me such that I heard it distinctly in my mind. This was one. I asked, and God said, “You don’t have to do this.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew exactly what He meant. I had been praying for weeks for opportunities to commit to Him more deeply. I knew, in that moment, He was giving me the chance to do just that. And as He does, He left the choice to me. He was offering me the choice between comfortable familiarity and adventure. Between the mundane and the mysterious. Between the theory of faith and its crazy, difficult reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I went. And now, six years later, I’m trying to figure out what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found out in this past year that so many of my attitudes about and approaches to ministry were flawed and unhealthy. I’ve learned that I was mentally and emotionally unhealthy in ways I didn’t understand at the time. But I learned and did a lot of good things, too. I’m just having a really hard time discerning between the two. I don’t know what things God allowed to be difficult to grow and mature me versus the things that were difficult because I wasn’t doing things His way. I don’t know whether I’m a failed pastor or… something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s in incredibly uncomfortable position to be in. Especially now that I’m going to be teaching a class on apologetics in the church I’ve been attending for just under a year. I don’t know what’s going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, and more importantly, I don’t know what I am. My identity got deeply tied into my position: I was a pastor, an official minister. Now I’m not. Am I going to be again? Is this class a step in that direction? Or will it confirm, through its inadequacy, that I was never meant to be a minister in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m knee-deep in questions whose immediate answer is all the same: listen to God. I have to accept, in the meantime, that I don’t know the answers, and keep following as best I can. That’s one big lesson I can definitely take away from all this: sometimes, you have to carry your questions with you as you walk and trust God to correct your path if you make a mistake. That’s essential to faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If nothing else, I’m learning to live by faith, not by fear. And if, for the rest of my life, that were the only thing I ever mastered, that would be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://razorclown.github.io/2015/10/08/Indeterminate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://razorclown.github.io/2015/10/08/Indeterminate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Christianity</category>
        
        <category>mental health</category>
        
        <category>ministry</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blue Pants vs. Brock Lesnar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I think it says something that a female wrestler named Blue Pants got a bigger pop than the guy who won this year’s Royal Rumble and headlined Wrestlemania. But what does it say? That wrestling fans are fickle hipsters? Or that whoever’s booking NXT could teach whoever’s booking the main roster how to do their job? Or that wrestling is more voodoo than science? I really don’t know. All I know is, I was seriously on board with NXT Takeover Brooklyn, but I was scratching my head at much of Summerslam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps a good illustration is the contrast between two matches: the NXT Tag Team Championship match, and the Title for Title match between Seth Rollins and John Cena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the face of it, the NXT Tag Team Championship match sounds idiotic: the defending champions, a pair of dubstep-loving bros and their evil cheerleader manager, face off against the fan favorites, a pair of vaudeville strongmen. Pure gimmicky stupidity? Hardly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vaudeville gimmick figures into the ongoing story, in which Alexa Bliss, the evil cheerleader, continually berates and slaps around the fan favorites, who refuse to fight back. In a recent episode, the crowd chanted “CHIVALRY! CHIVALRY!” to encourage the Vaudevillains to keep their composure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrestling fans, chanting for chivalry. Let that sink in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, in an interview, our heroes assure us that they will soon have an answer to the Alexa Bliss problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Takeover, the Vaudevillains make their way to the ring without anyone accompanying them, but when Bliss insults them and is about to slap them, they motion calmly for her to stop and gesture politely to the entrance ramp. Out comes Blue Pants with a Vaudevillains shirt. The crowd goes insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind you, this wasn’t even a surprise. The NXT fans had been chanting for Blue Pants to come stomp Bliss for weeks. Predictable? Obviously. But based on the crowd reaction, no less awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment when the two women finally fought was telling. Bliss stepped into the ring at a critical moment, ready to attack the Vaudevillains and cause a disqualification, giving up the victory but allowing Blake and Murphy to retain their championship. At this moment, Blue Pants jumps in, trouncing the evil cheerleader and keeping the match going, which the Vaudevillains eventually win clean. “That should have been a disqualification right there!” says Corey Graves, the heel announcer, followed by perhaps the greatest call in recent memory: “Blue Pants, you’ve ruined everything!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my thought process going into this match:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blake and Murphy are bad guys because they are mean and they cheat. I buy that. I hope they lose.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexa Bliss is a bad guy because she is mean to the guys that are trying to do the right thing and she cheats. I buy that. I hope she gets taught a lesson.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Vaudevillains are good guys because they are entertaining and chivalrous. I buy that. I hope they win.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Vaudevillains need a female wrestler to help them. Hey, Blue Pants has a similar goofy charm and is really entertaining. I hope she shows up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what happens? Blue Pants shows up, gives Alexa Bliss what for, and helps the Vaudevillains win a decisive victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrast that with my thought process going into the Cena/Rollins match:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rollins is a bad guy because he is a self-aggrandizing jerk and won his title in a sleazy way. Lately, however, he’s shown a lot of independence from his sleazy corporate masters. He also has a flashy, high-risk style that’s really fun to watch. And his promo from the other night on RAW was really good-guy-ish. But… yeah, he’s the bad guy. But does WWE think I’m supposed to think he’s the bad guy?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John Cena is the good guy because he never gives up and fights clean. I buy that. But not a lot of people do, sounds like. And as much as I like him, I’m really not interested in another John Cena title run, so… yes, he’s the good guy, but I don’t want him to win. Wait, does the WWE know that a large portion of their audience thinks similarly, or do they think we’re supposed to want him to win?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Okay, Rollins is the bad guy, but I’d rather see him win than the good guy. So, if Rollins is going to win, I want him to do something dastardly and win, so he can keep being a good bad guy and Cena can… do… something else. Yeah, there we go. Or he could turn into a good guy! Wait, would that make sense?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what happens? Cena and Rollins have an exceptional match until the referee gets knocked out and — wait for it — Summerslam host Jon Stewart runs out and hits Cena with a chair. Rollins then hits his finisher in time for the ref to wake up and count three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes less sense when you remember that Rollins and Stewart had a feud a few months ago. Honestly, I didn’t even remember that when Stewart ran out at Summerslam. If I had, I’d have thought, ”oh, sure, he’s going to hit Rollins,” which, now that I think of it, wouldn’t have made terribly much sense, since that feud ended with Stewart kicking Rollins in the junk and making his escape. It was resolved, and I didn’t hear any references to it leading up to the match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing I can figure is that they’re setting up Stewart for an upcoming role on television, perhaps as the heel general manager of RAW or the like. That would be a cool surprise. Whatever the reason, I was left totally confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: Stewart explained on RAW the following night that he did it to preserve Ric Flair’s record of 16 title reigns. While this set up a moderately funny exchange between him and John Cena, I’m not buying it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In storytelling, there is a balance to be struck between the audience’s expectation, plain logic, dramatic timing, and what the story needs structurally. Often, the ideal scenario is not to surprise the audience with an ending, but rather to let them anticipate and hope for it. An obvious ending that the audience is looking forward to is usually better than one they didn’t see coming, but to which they have no idea how to react.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ending to the Vaudevillains’ feud with Blake and Murphy was so obvious as to be inevitable. The setup led invariably to the conclusion. And at the conclusion, the people cheered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cena/Rollins feud, on the other hand, may or may not even be over. The setup and the conclusion are basically unrelated. The end of their match was, in essence, a deus ex machina: it happened that way for no better reason than because the writers say so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be surprised at someone criticizing a wrestling show for bad storytelling. &lt;em&gt;Isn’t that kind of like criticizing a boxer for having bad grammar?&lt;/em&gt; you may think. &lt;em&gt;That’s kinda not the point.&lt;/em&gt; But for me, it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started watching wrestling because it gave me a series of theatrical, acrobatic fight scenes. I kept watching wrestling as I grew to enjoy the characters and their interactions. Watching a wrestling match is one thing. Watching a match between the valiant underdog that’s been denied justice for months and the villain you love to hate — that’s different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when you’ve seen it done well, you come to expect better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://razorclown.github.io/2015/08/25/blue-pants-vs-brock-lesnar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://razorclown.github.io/2015/08/25/blue-pants-vs-brock-lesnar.html</guid>
        
        <category>entertainment</category>
        
        <category>wrestling</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Too Close to Hate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had been a Christian for years, but I hated myself. That shouldn’t be possible, but I did. I was preaching grace, but showing myself none. It struck me one night as I sat in my apartment. &lt;em&gt;I really dfo hate myself&lt;/em&gt;, I thought. I realized how wrong that was, and that it needed to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not an easy thing to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a lot of prayer to get there. In particular, one especially powerful prayer and the agency of God in addressing the lies I’d come to believe about myself. Honestly, it took supernatural healing. There was a moment that God did something, and ever since, I have not been able to honestly say that I hate myself. He did something in me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What remains to be overcome is my hatred of imperfection. That still remains. I hate my own flaws, in that drains me of grace when I encounter other people’s flaws. When people make mistakes, I’m extremely intolerant. I think it’s because I fought so hard not to make mistakes in my life. I see other people not fighting as hard — that is, being happier and freer — I react very strongly against that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m especially intolerant of Christians making mistakes. &lt;em&gt;You’re making us look bad&lt;/em&gt;, I think. To be honest, I’ve had some horrible thoughts about Christians who I think have low intelligence. I can’t bear to think how that makes us look in the eyes of a culture that already thinks of us as stupid and misled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I was taught that, essentially, mistakes are sins. I can’t remember anyone ever actually saying that, but I think it’s something a lot of influential people in my life implied very heavily, at least by their actions. Somehow, I came to believe that all mistakes are the result of negligence or some other personal deficiency. If you forget what somebody says, it’s because you weren’t paying close enough attention. If you were shown how to do something right but it didn’t do it, you don’t care enough to do it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is, one way or another, I learned these mistaken ideas so thoroughly that they still sound right to me. They still seem kind of reasonable. I’m having to fight hard to remember that there is such a thing as a mistake. I have to check myself, tell myself the truth over and over until it &lt;em&gt;sounds&lt;/em&gt; true to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my recent fight against all this, I read a book called &lt;em&gt;The Search for Significance&lt;/em&gt;. In it, the author addresses several common lies that people believe, which leads them toward depression. One of those lies is that if you are imperfect, you are unworthy of love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I read that, I realized how deeply I believed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being a Christian pastor for several years, despite believing wholeheartedly in the love and grace of God, something deep inside me still believed that because I was not flawless in my every word and deed, I was not worthy to be loved by anyone. I also realized that I believed this very deeply for myself, but not for others. Mind you, I knew intellectually that God’s love and grace extend to everyone including me. I accepted that. I just didn’t feel it. That’s what I mean when I say that I believed myself unworthy of love. I didn’t feel worthy of love. Something deep in my being would not allow what I believed in my mind to reach my heart. Not where it concerned myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I began recently rereading the Psalms, there was one that stood out to me. In Psalm 62, David says that his soul finds rest in God. Now, “soul” is one of those words that deserves looking up. We may have grown up with any number of ideas about what the soul really is, but what David means when he says it is the deepest inner self, that place in us that drives our choices and everything else that makes us &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What David is saying is, his self finds rest in God. And when I read that, I realized how badly I wanted it. That is what I am doing now. Not just to believe, but to believe wholeheartedly and with all of my being, to be so secure in my belief that it dismantles my deepest insecurities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in God. I put my trust in Jesus. I know for a fact that I am saved. I just need my heart to know that in a new way. And I know that when I do, it will change everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://razorclown.github.io/2014/10/14/too-close-to-hate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://razorclown.github.io/2014/10/14/too-close-to-hate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Christianity</category>
        
        <category>mental health</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
